In this video, I'm going to demonstrate
how you can input information to
the spreadsheet and apply some
formatting to that information.
As you can see on the screen in front of
me, I have a Word document that contains
a table with information relating to
the sales for the different experiences
at the Flyaway Balloon Company.
I've also got some instructions
as to what I need to do to that.
But in this video, all I need to do is
to actually transfer the information
and enter it into the spreadsheet.
So the first thing I need to
do is open a new spreadsheet
and I've got one already open.
So I just bring that up and I'll
just line that up with the Word
document so you can see them both now.
There are two ways I can actually get
the information in there so I can simply
have them side by side on the screen
and then begin by clicking in cell
A1 and then start typing the names.
So it duplicates what's
actually in the Word document.
A quicker way than doing that is just
to click on the table icon in the
Word document, so all of the table
is highlighted, then select Control
and C, which will then copy to the
clipboard, then click in cell A1 on
the spreadsheet and select Control
in V which will then paste it.
Now you can see it has changed
the formatting slightly, the
January sales, all their column
headings, they're all a little bit
compressed, the words in column A.
Now, we've got two options.
If you look down at the right-hand
side, you've got your paste options
and you have two options here.
You can keep the source formatting
or match the destination formatting.
In this instance, I'm going to
match the destination formatting.
That has slightly changed the
layout, but it's still not perfect.
Some of the headings aren't clear and
some of the words and the text in column
A isn't clear at all, but that's something
that we will look at in a moment.
So now that I have all the information
in there, I can begin making changes.
And as we work through each of the
sessions, you will make changes to this
information and add certain elements.
But the first thing to be aware of
is that as we've got the information
in here, as you can see some of
the information has truncated.
What we need to do is
to make sure it's clear.
So what I can do I can click in
between each of the column headings,
so in between A and B, and then I can
manually widen the columns to make sure
that all of the information is clear
and I can do that for the January and
February and March sales and so on.
A quicker way of doing that is I'm
just going to undo what I did there.
Just so we can show you how
to do this a lot quicker.
If I click on the little triangle at
the top, as you can see, the whole
of the worksheet has now gone gray.
So if I now double clicked in between
columns A and B and I double-click
there, it will automatically
resize all of the column width
so that all of the data is clear.
So that's one way of doing it.
And alternatively, again, I'll
just compress the columns a bit.
Even just by simply double clicking on
the line between column A and B, just
for that column -  if I only want to
widen one column and double click on
it, it will automatically change that.
Similarly, January sales, February sales,
March sales, April sales, and so on.
So now that I have all the information
in there, I'm going to apply some
formatting to the information.
And a good way of doing that is you,
rather than individually selecting each
cell, you can highlight a range of data.
So for example, if I highlight and click
and hold, so I click and hold on cell
B2, and then just drag the mouse down
and along, I've now selected all of the
numerical data and at the moment, if
you look up on the number section it is
saying that is number format, and I'm
going to just click on that dropdown
and I'm going to change it to currency.
And as you can see that has
applied currency formatting to
all of the data within there.
Similarly, I can go down and I could
change it to percentages and it
will show as percentages, or I can
have it as number or just general.
So as you can see, you can apply
a specific type of formatting
to a range of information.
Now in the price column, this number,
are all of the numbers in this column,
they should be in currency format.
So rather than individually going in and
changing that I can highlight all of the
information and then select currency.
But another way of doing that is
if I wanted to make sure that all
of the information in that column
moving forward was set as currency.
All I would do is change that to currency.
So now, anything that I type in
there as you can see when I click
in different cells but if I click on
that cell it changes back to general,
but anything in that column will
automatically be formatted as currency.
And if, for example, you had a
large figure, it will automatically
widen the column to fit that now.
And it will automatically change
it to currency formatting.
So I'll just u that.
So that's the information we have.
There may be occasions where you need
to insert images within a spreadsheet.
It's not very common, but if you did,
it is exactly the same as you would
do to insert an image within your
Word or a presentation document, you
would simply go to the insert tab.
And then from the illustrations
section, you would select picture.
And wherever you have the image located
and in this instance, it will be in the
documents inside of my ITQ folder, and
the image can be inserted like that.
Again, obviously you can move that around.
If you wish to place this in a
specific place so it will be locked
to a specific place, I have provided
instructions on how to do that.
And you may want to have a look at that
and you can also insert it into the
header or the footer of the document,
which would then enable you when you
printed the spreadsheets, it would be
able to be shown in the header or footer.
It wouldn't show in the header or footer
by default on the actual screen once
you use the header and footer, but
that's something we'll cover later on.